Melissa Murphy



linkedin.com/in/melissamurphy



https://mm-dev-portfolio.firebaseapp.com/



hello@melissamurphy.io

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with experience in Marketing, Business Development, and a demonstrated history of working in the construction and nonprofit industries. Skilled in Client Relations, Front End Dev (SASS, Git, strong design skills), Back End (Firebase), Adobe Suite, Google Analytics/AdSense. Creative and engaged professional with a Bachelor of Arts (B.A.) focused in American History (United States) from California State University-Sacramento (which means I can research like a boss).

Experience



Section Lead - Full Stack Web

Lambda School

Jul 2019 - Present (9 months +)

- Manage 7-14 Team Leaders, as well as facilitate communication and scheduling with TLs from outside
- Mentor team leads and students in developing soft skills in addition to coding skills
- Guiding ~150 students through their full stack web development program
- Assisted in the development of the new support hours now offered to new cohorts
- Work closely with section instructors to improve student outcomes
- Track data points and student feedback, and generate new coaching ideas from the statistics
- Extensive code reviews and additional teaching

Freelance Web Developer

Self-employed

Jan 2016 - Present (4 years 3 months +)

I provide various web development, graphic design, and marketing services for small businesses in and around the SF Bay Area. I love this work as it gives me a chance to share and create new ideas with business owners who are passionate about their industry.

I have flexible commitments with options for project-based, hourly, and retainer agreements.

Business Development Director/Webmaster

GLI Norcal Landscape Construction

Nov 2012 - Apr 2019 (6 years 6 months)

Responsible for all aspects of marketing, web development, and web presence. As we are a small company, we wear many hats. In my case, I also fill in as IT and general idea generator.

Outreach Specialist

American Cancer Society

Apr 2012 - Nov 2012 (8 months)

Recruited team members for participation in the Sacramento Making Strides Against Breast Cancer Walk. Managed and tracked Blue Ribbon Teams, which generated a minimum level \$2000 in donations. Managed and distributed weekly reports pertaining to overall numbers for the Walk. Assisted with organizing the event, and lead-up events, and was the primary organizer for the entertainment line-up. The 2012

Outreach Team was very successful, raising more than \$30,000 beyond the 2012 goal, for a total of \$480,000.

Customer Credit Specialist

Headsets.com

2004 - 2006 (3 years)

Sought past due payment by way of phone, mail, and facsimile. Successful collection rate was more than double the historical average. Was originally hired as a Customer Service Representative, promoted to Technical Support after three months, and promoted to Collections Specialist four months following.

Executive Director and Co-Founder

Shadowbox Theatre Productions, Inc.

2002 - 2004 (3 years)

Conceived, designed, and implemented an innovative program that provided after-school theatre programs for at-risk youth. Successfully obtained 501(c) 3 nonprofit status. Performed office and employee management, grant writing and development, liaison with local schools and community centers.

Business to Business Representative and Trainer

Wireless Stockroom

1998 - 2001 (4 years)

Provided phone based customer service and sales, managed a team of more than twelve, and provided training for new employees.

Education



California State University-Sacramento

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), American History (United States) 2008 - 2011

Lambda School

Computer Science

2019 - 2019

current student, Full Stack Engineer

Monroe Community College

Associate of Science (A.S.), Liberal Arts and Sciences, General Studies and Humanities 2006 - 2008

Honors & Awards



Graduated Magna Cum Laude - California State University, Sacramento



Graduated with Honors - Monroe Community College

Skills

HTML 5 • CSS • JavaScript • Adobe Creative Suite • Management • Program Management • Django • Python (Programming Language) • Node.js • User Experience (UX)